# Mark Barone

720 Glastonbury Court, Cumming GA 30041

Mobile: 404-422-7129

*Email*: mark@mark-barone.com

github.com/baronema

= mark-barone.com

in linkedin.com/in/mark-barone-546128145

## ENTRY LEVEL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## **SUMMARY**

Seven plus years of experience with the proven ability to diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve technical problems in a time sensitive/high stress environment. Exceptional customer service and communication skills; consistently conveys competence and attentiveness while engaging with clients and co-workers alike.

## **PROJECTS**

# Bookshelf - An intra-classroom library management and loan app built using Node.js, Express, MongoDB

- Implemented an authentication system for login and library loans using the Passport NPM package
- Created custom ISBN lookup search bar to automate new book additions by utilizing Node-ISBN API
- Developed MongoDB schema for data persistence hosted via mLab subscription

# Assessment Tool – An observation-based assessment platform for tracking early learning development

- Designed custom user interface according to teacher recommendations using the JavaFX library
- Created an authentication server for user login requests passed over a multithreaded socket connection
- Increased teacher efficiency by eliminating paper-based

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java | C++ | JavaScript | jQuery | Node.js | Express | HTML | CSS

#### WORK HISTORY

IT Field Technician. 10/2017 to 3/2018

**Brooksource** – Roswell, GA

• Responsible for the I.T. infrastructure upgrade of more than 2000 assets at North Fulton WellStar Hospital as part of the hospitals EPIC System integration, helping to achieve a successful Go-Live within a 12-month period

**Independent Contractor**, 02/2013 to 9/2017

True Carpentry – Greater Atlanta Area

Developed a custom company website which has increased overall annual sales by 10% each of the past two years

**Engineering Technician III**, 02/2012 – 01/2013

CGI Federal - Jacksonville, NC

 Established an onsite component level repair shop greatly improving the number of available replacement processing units and displays on hand, thus reducing item procurement and shipping costs by 30%

Communications Technician, 11/2005 to 04/2011

United States Marine Corps – Kaneohe Bay, HI

 Performed diagnostic testing and troubleshooting of various communications equipment, managed help desk tickets, and maintained equipment inventory and maintenance logs

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2014 to 2017

Regis University - Denver, CO

Graduated Magna Cum Laude (3.75 / 4.0)

# **Courses included:**

Modern Software Engineering Java Development

Computer Systems Security Data Networks

Object-Oriented Development Unix OS